webshare.co 2013-03-28

# Privacy Policy | WebShare | Sharing The Web With Friends

## WebShare Privacy Policy

Questions. If you have any questions or concerns about our privacy policy, contact our privacy team through the contact page. 

Scope. This privacy policy covers all of WebShare. It does not, however, apply to entities that WebShare does not own or control, such as websites posted on WebShare. By using or accessing WebShare, you agree to our privacy practices outlined here. 

Parental participation. We strongly recommend that minors 13 years of age or older ask their parents for permission before sending any information about themselves to anyone over the Internet and we encourage parents to teach their children about safe internet use practices. If you have any questions regarding the use of this site by anyone under 13 please use the contact form. 

Information We Receive 

Information you provide to us: 

Information About Yourself. When you sign up forWebShare you provide us with your name, email, and birth date. You will also be able to add a picture of yourself. In some cases we may ask for additional information for security reasons or to provide specific services to you. 

Content. One of the primary reasons people use WebShare is to share content with others. Examples include links to photos, videos, general web links, comments on your WebShares and comments on friends WebShares. Please be aware that we cannot guarantee the security of this information although we try our best to protect it. When you post a comment, your username and the comment can be viewed by your friend's friends. 

Site activity information. We keep track of some of the actions you take on WebShare, such as adding a friend. In some cases you are also taking an action when you provide information or content to us. For example, if you share a WebShare, in addition to storing the actual content you uploaded, we might log the fact that you shared it. 

Access Device and Browser Information. When you access WebShare from a computer, mobile phone, or other device, we may collect information from that device about your browser type, location, and IP address, as well as the pages you visit. 

Cookie Information. We use "cookies" (small pieces of data we store for an extended period of time on your computer, mobile phone, or other device) to make WebShare easier to use, to make our advertising better, and to protect both you and WebShare. For example, we use them to store your login ID (but never your password) to make it easier for you to login whenever you come back to WebShare. We also use them to confirm that you are logged into WebShare, and to know when you are interacting with websites, our widgets and buttons, and our advertisements. You can remove or block cookies using the settings in your browser, but in some cases that may impact your ability to use WebShare. 

Name and Profile Picture. WebShare is designed to make it easy for you to find and connect with others. For this reason, your name and profile picture do not have privacy settings. If you are uncomfortable with sharing your profile picture, you should delete it (or not add one). When using a public search engines your username and name for your invite friends page may appear. If you this is a concern to you, you may change your screen name in the edit details page (please note this will change your screen name for your current friends). 

**Date of Birth. In addition to name and email address, we require you to provide your date of birth during the registration process. We ask for your date of birth so we can restrict certain content if needed and advertisements that are not age appropriate. Because your date of birth is required, you cannot delete it. This information will not be made available to any of your friends. If you have any questions regarding your Date of Birth you can contact us using the contact form on the contact page.**

Even after you remove information from your profile or delete your account, copies of that information may remain viewable elsewhere to the extent it has been shared with others, it was otherwise distributed pursuant to your, or it was copied or stored by other users. 

You understand that information might be reshared or copied by other users. 

Minors. We reserve the right to add special protections for minors (such as to provide them with an age-appropriate experience) and place restrictions on the ability of adults to share and connect with minors, recognizing this may provide minors a more limited experience on WebShare. 

Advertisements. Sometimes the advertisers who present ads on WebShare require technological methods to measure the effectiveness of their ads and to personalize advertising content. You will only be targetted via the category you clicked on not by the previous categories you have clicked on. You may opt-out of the placement of cookies by many of these advertisers by contacting us using the contact form on the cotact page stating you do not want cookies stored on your computer from advertiser. You may also use your browser cookie settings to limit or prevent the placement of cookies by advertising networks. WebShare does not share personally identifiable information. 

Links. When you click on links on WebShare you may leave our site. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of other sites, and we encourage you to read their privacy statements. 

How We Use Your Information 

We use the information we collect to try to provide a safe, efficient, and customized experience. Here are some of the details on how we do that: 

To manage the service. We use the information we collect to provide our services and features to you, to measure and improve those services and features, and to provide you with customer support. We use the information to prevent potentially illegal activities, and to enforce our terms and conditions. We also use a variety of technological systems to detect and address anomalous activity and screen content to prevent abuse such as spam. These efforts may on occasion result in a temporary or permanent suspension or termination of some functions for some users. 

To contact you. We may contact you with service-related announcements from time to time. You may opt out of all communications except essential updates on your edit details page. We may include content you see on WebShare in the emails we send to you. 

To serve personalized advertising to you. We don't share your information with advertisers. Even though we do not share your information with advertisers, when you click on or otherwise interact with an advertisement there is a possibility that the advertiser may place a cookie in your browser and note that it meets the criteria they selected. 

To help your friends find you. We allow other users to use contact information they have about you, such as your email address, to find you, including through contact importers and search. You can prevent other users from using your email address to find you using the search section of your edit details page. 

Memorializing Accounts. If we are notified that a user is deceased, we may memorialize the user's account. In such cases we restrict profile access to confirmed friends. We may close an account if we receive a formal request from the user's next of kin or other proper legal request to do so. 

WebShare is about sharing information and websites with others — friends and people in your communities — while providing you withprivacy settings that you can use to restrict other users from accessing some of your information. We share your information with third parties when we believe the sharing is permitted by you, reasonably necessary to offer our services, or when legally required to do so. For example: 

When you invite a friend to join. When you ask us to invite a friend to join WebShare, we will send your friend a message on your behalf using your name. The invitation may also contain information about other users your friend might know. We may also send up to two reminders to them in your name. You can see who has accepted your invitations, send reminders, and delete your friends' email addresses on your invite history page. If your friend does not want us to keep their information, we will also remove it at their request. 

**You cannot search a name or username but it is possible to get that from other means such as google. This is the only information that is publicly available.**

To respond to legal requests and prevent harm. We may disclose information pursuant to court orders, or other requests (including criminal and civil matters) if we have a good faith belief that the response is required by law. This may include respecting requests from jurisdictions outside of the United Kingdom where we have a good faith belief that the response is required by law under the local laws in that jurisdiction, apply to users from that jurisdiction, and are consistent with generally accepted international standards. We may also share information when we have a good faith belief it is necessary to prevent fraud or other illegal activity, to prevent imminent bodily harm, or to protect ourselves and you from people violating our termsn and conditions. This may include sharing information with other companies, lawyers, courts or other government entities. 

How You Can Change or Remove Information 

Delete uploaded contacts. If you would like to delete friends please contact us at webshare@webshare.co via your registered email or use the contact form on the contact us page. 

Deactivating or deleting your account. If you want to stop using your account you may deactivate it or delete it. When you deactivate an account, no user will be able to see it, but it will not be deleted. We save your profile information (connections, photos, etc.) in case you later decide to reactivate your account. Many users deactivate their accounts for temporary reasons and in doing so are asking us to maintain their information until they return to WebShare. You will still have the ability to reactivate your account and restore your profile in its entirety. When you delete an account, it is permanently deleted from WebShare. You should only delete your account if you are certain you never want to reactivate it. You may deactivate or delete your account by sending an email to webshare@webshare.co from your registered email address. 

Limitations on removal. Posts will stay. 

Even after you remove information from your profile or delete your account, copies of that information may remain viewable elsewhere to the extent it has been shared with others, or it was copied or stored by other users. Additionally, we may retain certain information to prevent identity theft and other misconduct even if deletion has been requested. 

Backup copies. Removed and deleted information may persist in backup copies for up to 90 days, but will not be available to others. 

Risks inherent in sharing information. Although we allow you to set privacy options that limit access to your information, please be aware that no security measures are perfect or impenetrable. We cannot control the actions of other users with whom you share your information. We cannot guarantee that only authorized persons will view your information. We cannot ensure that information you share on WebShare will not become publicly available. We are not responsible for third party circumvention of any privacy settings or security measures on WebShare. You can reduce these risks by using common sense security practices such as choosing a strong password, using different passwords for different services, and using up to date antivirus software. 

Report Violations. You should report any security violations to us on via our coutact form on the contact us page. 

Changes. We may change this Privacy Policy pursuant to the procedures outlined in the WebShare terms and conditions. Unless stated otherwise, our current privacy policy applies to all information that we have about you and your account. 

Consent to Collection and Processing in the United Kingdom. By using WebShare, you consent to having your personal data transferred to and processed in the United Kingdom. 

Defined Terms."Us," "we," "our," "Platform" and "WebShare" mean the same as they do in the terms and conditions. "Information" and "content" are used more generally and interchangeably here than in the terms and conditions unless otherwise limited by the context.
